ILGWU. Local 62. Managers' correspondence 5780/079
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Local 62. Managers' correspondence
1941-1981
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Schoenwald, Matthew
Local 62
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/079
4 cubic feet
4 linear ft.
Correspondence, records, reports.
The collection consists primarily of correspondence of Local 62's manager, Matthew Schoenwald. Corrrespondents include staff in several of the ILGWU departments, as well as Louis Stulberg, David Dubinsky, and Executive Director of The Lingerie Manufacturers Association Jack Gross. Also included are records documenting the work of the Liberal Party, including correspondence and mailing lists.
6322549
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
B. Walker, September 26, 2008
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, June 10, 2014
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Biographical / Historical
The White Goods Workers' Union Local 62, also known as the Underwear and White Goods Workers Union, was chartered in 1909, but was not fully organized until 1913. Rose Schneiderman and the Women's Trade Union League assisted with the early organizing efforts of the White Goods Workers. These workers consisted mainly of young immigrant girls. Early leaders of the local included Samuel Shore. On March 1913, 15,000 workers went on strike against the sweatshop conditions. A six week strike ensued in which many of the girls on the picket lines were attacked and arrested. Gains won included a 54 hour week, no Sunday, sanitary conditions and an 18 cent an hour minimum wage. This strike made the local.
The local and its workers were originally called white goods workers as they manufactured camisoles, chemises, cambric drawers with lace ruffles and drawstrings, and corset covers. Through the years, styles changed and production shifted to panties and slips. In the 1960s, the local became the Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union Local 62.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists primarily of correspondence of Local 62's manager Matthew Schoenwald. Correspondents include staff in several of the ILGWU departments, as well as Presidents Louis Stulberg and David Dubinsky, James Lipsig (Assistant Executive Secretary) and Jack Gross. Gross was the Executive Director for The Lingerie Manufacturers Association, Inc. and The Negligee Manufacturers Association, Inc. and his files include correspondence and agreements. Additionally, there is correspondence and agreements with the manufacturer association for the undergarment industry, the Allied Underwear Association, Inc.
General administrative records detailing the work of Local 62 includes correspondence regarding the benefit and retirement funds. Associated Hospital Service refers to the Blue Cross Plan of the local, and there are terms of benefits, claims, payments, and providers. There are Local 62 reports to the General Office, documents of the Office Workers Division of Local 62, meetings, and collective agreements for office employees in shops. Celebrations are documented through anniversaries, Unity House outings, and luncheons.
There are a large amount of files and correspondence with the lawyers that represented Local 62 on arbitration cases, including the firms of Lieberman, Aronson and Rosenberg as well as Lieberman, Katz and Aronson, which were headed by Elias Lieberman. The Lieberman, Katz and Aronson firm were also counsel to the Retirement Fund and were present at Fund meetings. The records contain meeting minutes, retirement applicants, finances, and rules and regulations.
Departments represented in the collection include the Auditing Department (year end and annual reports, strike collections and receipts, tally sheets on investments and dues, signed and completed annual forms) and the Northeast Department. Local 62 worked closely with this department regarding underwear and lingerie shops outside of New York City, and communicated locations of shops and their agreements to the Northeast Department.
There is much information documenting the work of the Liberal Party and elections, as Matthew Schoenwald was a candidate for the 27th Assembly District for Queens County. Available is correspondence on meetings, contributions, campaigns, fundraising, and lists of individuals residing in districts.
In his role as a union vice president, Shoenwald also helped organize undergarment and lingerie shops in other areas, particularly Puerto Rico.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/021: ILGWU. Local 62 records 5780/022: ILGWU. Local 62 correspondence 5780/074: ILGWU. Mary Goff Schuster papers 5780/089: ILGWU. Local 62-32 agreements
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Women's clothing industry -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- United States; Clothing workers -- New York (State) -- New York; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 62 (New York, N.Y.)
6322549
- Wage-Hour Schedules (4 copies), no dates (Box 1, Folder 1)
- ILGWU - James Lipsig, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- ILGWU - James Lipsig, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- ILGWU - James Lipsig, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Liberal Party, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Liberal Party, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Liberal Party, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Liberal Party, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Liberal Party, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Liberal Party, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Jewish Occupational Council, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Jewish Labor Committee, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Office Employees (165A) Local 62 Shops, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Office Workers Division Collective Agreements (Assn's) (165A), 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Office Employees (165A) Local 62 Shops, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- ILGWU Auditing Department, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- ILGWU Auditing Department, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- ILGWU Auditing Department, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- ILGWU Auditing Department, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- ILGWU Auditing Department, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- ILGWU Auditing Department, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- ILGWU Auditing Department, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- ILGWU Northeast Department, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- ILGWU Northeast Department, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- ILGWU Northeast Department (special), 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- ILGWU Northeast Department, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- ILGWU Northeast Department, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- ILGWU Northeast Department Agreement (Box 1, Folder 28)
- ILGWU Puerto Rico Region, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- ILGWU Puerto Rico Region, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- ILGWU Puerto Rico Region, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- ILGWU Research Department, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- ILGWU Research Department, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- ILGWU Retiree Services Department, 1968-1975 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Retirees - Misc. Locals Meeting, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- ILGWU Special Assistance Fund, 1967-1977 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- ILGWU Special Assistance Fund, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Impartial Chairman, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Miscellaneous Member Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Miscellaneous Member Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Miscellaneous Member Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Miscellaneous Member Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Vanity Fair, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- U.S. Lingerie [folder 1 of 2], 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- U.S. Lingerie [folder 2 of 2], 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- U.S. Pay Board, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- U.S. Pay Board [folder 1 of 2], 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- U.S. Pay Board [folder 2 of 2], 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Associated Hospital Service, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Associated Hospital Service, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Associated Hospital Service, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Associated Hospital Service, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Associated Hospital Service, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Associated Hospital Service, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Blue Cross, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Celebrations, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Celebrations [folder 1 of 2], 1941-1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Celebrations [folder 2 of 2], 1941-1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Chairladies' Notices, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Chairladies' Notices, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Chairladies' Notices, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Chairladies' Notices, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Contributions, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Contributions, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Contributions, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Contributions, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- ILGWU - Louis Stulberg, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- ILGWU - Louis Stulberg, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- ILGWU - Louis Stulberg, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- ILGWU - Louis Stulberg, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- ILGWU - Louis Stulberg, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- ILGWU - David Dubinsky, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- ILGWU - David Dubinsky, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- ILGWU - David Dubinsky, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- ILGWU - David Dubinsky, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Fifth Avenue Robes, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- ILGWU - Local 122, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- ILGWU - Local 107, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- ILGWU - Louis Stulberg, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- ILGWU - Louis Stulberg, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- ILGWU - Louis Stulberg, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- ILGWU - Louis Stulberg, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- ILGWU - Louis Stulberg, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Lieberman, Aronson and Rosenberg, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Lieberman, Aronson and Rosenberg, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Lieberman, Aronson and Rosenberg, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Lieberman, Aronson and Rosenberg, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Lieberman, Aronson and Rosenberg, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Lieberman, Aronson and Rosenberg, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Lieberman, Aronson and Rosenberg, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Lieberman, Katz and Aronson, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Lieberman, Katz and Aronson, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Lieberman, Katz and Aronson, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Lieberman, Katz and Aronson, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Lieberman, Katz and Aronson, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Lieberman, Katz and Aronson, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Lieberman, Katz and Aronson, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Lieberman, Katz and Aronson, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Lieberman, Katz and Aronson, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Retirement Fund Meetings, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Retirement Fund Meetings, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Retirement Fund Meetings, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- For Retirement Fund Meeting, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Retirement Fund, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Retirement Fund - Finance Committee re Investments, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Retirement Fund - Rules (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Child-Fit, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Barsa, Odette (Fresoeur), 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Betty Page Togs, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Baker, Zorita (member), 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Allied Underwear Association, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Allied Underwear Association, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Allied Underwear Association, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Allied Underwear Association, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Allied Underwear Association, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Allied Underwear Association, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Allied Underwear Association, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Allied Underwear Association, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Allied Underwear Association, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Allied Underwear Association, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Allied Underwear Association, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Contractors' Association, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Jack Gross, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Jack Gross, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Jack Gross, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Jack Gross, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Jack Gross, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Jack Gross, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Jack Gross, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Jack Gross, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Jack Gross, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Jack Gross, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Jack Gross, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Jack Gross, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Style Undies, 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Style Undies, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Style Undies, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Style Undies, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Superior Petticoat, 1970-1975 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Superior Petticoat, 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Superior Petticoat - memo by and between Local 62, 1963-1968 (Box 4, Folder 43)